Xinyu Liu

(650) 399-5726 ♦ liuxinyulxy333@gmail.com ♦ San Francisco, CA ♦ LinkedIn ♦ GitHub

PROFILE

With 3 years of experience as a data science and business analytics professional across start-ups and Fortune 500 firms, I bring a unique blend of technical expertise and business insights to fuel digital product growth and market expansion. **Specialties**: Data Analysis, Statistical Analysis, Machine Learning, Online Experimentation, Product Management **Technologies**: Python (NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, PySpark), R (ggplot2, dplyr), SQL, Excel, Tableau, HTML, CSS **Certifications**: HackerRank SQL Adv. Certificate, Tableau Desktop Specialist, Google Analytics Professional Certificate

EDUCATION

University of California, Davis

San Francisco, CA

Aug. 2022 - Jun. 2023

Master of Science, Business Analytics

Awards: Dean's Fellowship; 2023 Aggies Hackathon 3rd Place Winner (sponsored by HP and Google Cloud)

Highlighted Coursework: Machine Learning; Big Data; Advanced Statistics; Data Management; Analytic Decision Making

Beijing Language and Culture University

Beijing, CHN

Bachelor of Business Administration, Accounting

Sep. 2017 - Jun. 2021

Awards: First Prize Scholarship (Top 10% of Class in 2019 and 2020); Merit Student (2019)

Highlighted Coursework: Corporate Strategy and Risk Management; Finance; Information System Management

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Savvy Aviation

San Francisco, CA

Data Scientist, MSBA Practicum Project

Sep. 2022 - Jun. 2023

Crafted an automated workflow for the AI-driven firm to streamline customer request classification and processing.

- Designed and implemented ML algorithms to classify and extract relevant information from ~1.8M historical customer service requests. Constructed a new MySQL database to store processed data.
- Automated the workflow for processing new service requests, utilizing AWS, Python, and SQL within the client's infrastructure. Reduced 10+ hours/week of manual logging for 6 maintenance managers.
- Led a team of 5 members for 3 major updates and implementations of customer success plans. Maintained weekly communication with managers and data engineers to facilitate workflow implementation.

TotalEnergies Beijing, CHN

Strategy Analyst Aug. 2021 – Jul. 2022 Assisted the Fortune 500 company in formulating business strategies through machine learning and market data analysis.

- Employed K-Means Clustering to segment 30K+ EV charging users into 5 distinct customer personas. Designed targeting online promotion strategies. Increased average profitability of 1K+ charging facilities by 6%.
 - Used web traffic capturing and web scraping to collect first-hand data of 20+ target companies to support \$1M+ M&A projects. Modeled the data for asset valuation and profitability forecast.
 - Automated social media and news monitoring to track competitor activities and regional policy updates. Optimized regional service price dynamically. Increased market share by ~5% in three major cities with optimized pricing.

TAL Education Group

Beijing, CHN

Business Analyst, Internship

Nov. 2020 - Mar. 2021

Improved the online education start-up's conversion rate and profitability with A/B testing and data-driven UX updates.

- Implemented A/B tests that involved 1K+ users for website UX design. Analyzed the result to support decision-making of major feature updates. Increased customer conversion rate by ~5% and active time by ~10%.
- Designed and executed 2 customer service surveys. Analyzed responses from 500+ customers. Conducted 60 hours of customer interviews to gather insights on specific issues. Generated insights to reduce churn by ~10%.
- Engaged in search engine keyword discovery and online ads click-through rate analysis. Analyzed social media attribution with Adobe Analytics. Summarized insights for weekly online marketing updates.

PROJECTS

NLP Project (Python): building a customized dictionary with keywords and phrases using CSV files as input.

<u>LASSO Regression Project (R)</u>: feature selection and model tuning for linear regression models using the LASSO method.

<u>Linear Optimization Project (Python):</u> finding optimal price and production with linear optimization.

KNN and K-Means Clustering (Python): classify, abstract key features, and make predictions of observations.